# 大家好 今天又沒菜吃啦
Hi everyone! I run out of food again today.
# 我去山上挖點那個竹笋 你看 這山上
I go onto the hill to get some, you know, some bamboo shoots. Look! That hill.
# 這個竹林很茂盛哦
The bamboo forest is really bushy.
# 哎呀 有一個
Aya! Here's one!
# 你看 這個竹笋很大哦 這個
Look! This bamboo shoot is really big, this one.
# 大竹笋
Big bamboo shoot
# 哎喲 這個 這個可以
Ayo! This one, this one is not bad.
# 你看
Look!
# 這個竹笋很漂亮的哦 你看
It's a really pretty bamboo shoot, look!
# 不大不小
Not too big, not too small
# 哎喲 有一個
Ayo! Here's one!
# 你看
Look!
# 這麼小的
It's so small.
# 好小這個
It's really small.
# 你看
Look!
# 也不小哦
It's not that small in fact.
# 你看
Look!
# 夠嫩 剛剛好
It's young, just right.
# 先把它放在這裡先
Let me put it here first.
# 哎喲 有一個
Ayo! Here's one,
# 好小哇
a tiny one!
# 這個那麼小
This one is so tiny.
# 又扁又小 你看 這個
It's flat and small. Look! This one
# 要 (註︰沒下文了)
I wanna...
# 我檢到一堆去
I have several over there.
# 放在那裡先
Put it there first.
# 哎呀 有一個
Aya! Here's one!
# 哎呀 這個挺大的哦 這個
Aya! It's rather large, this one.
# 哎呀 不大 剛剛那個不大 (註︰我想他是想說︰「不比剛剛那個大」)
Aya! No, it's not that large.
# 這個小哇 小短腿
It's small, with short legs.
# 你看 是不是
Look! Isn't it?
# 一看就看得出來
I can tell immediately.
# 你看
Look!
# 還可以哦 這個
It's not bad, this one.
# 你看 就挖了這三四個
Look! I've got a couple of them here.
# 現在下雨了啊
It's raining now.
# 回去啦
Let's head back.
# 夠吃一餐啦
It's enough for a meal.